# 油温七成热
Oil temperature is about 210°C
# 鸡爪子捞在冰水里边 激一下
Put chicken feet in ice water to make it shrink a little bit
# 做这个关键
The key to make this dish:
# 咱得在水里边来点麦芽糖
add some maltose
# 为了让它上色
for coloring.
# 把它在水里化开了
Dissolve it completely
# 你可以搁点白醋
You can add some white vinegar
# 炸出来更上色 还去腥
for better coloring and to remove the blood smell.
# 咱们听师父的加点米醋
Let's heed master's words and add some rice vinegar
# 师父是关键时候给你指点迷津
You master gives clarifications at the right moment
# 搁醋主要是去腥
Add vinegar to remove the blood smell
# 咱把这温水下锅 飞一下水
Warm water. Put the chicken feet in and boil a little bit.
# 凤爪
Chicken feet
# 你看前面那指甲全都剪掉了
You see the nails are all clipped
# 又脏又有味道
They are dirty and smelly
# 这就跟人一样讲卫生
Remain hygienic just like humans do
# 你知道吗
You know?
# 勤剪指甲
Clip nails regularly
# 水开了
The water is boiling
# 开了就可以了
Stop when it's boiling
# 这凤爪够肥的
These chicken feet are quite large
# 大爷您看咱们烧着油了
Da Ye you see we have the oil heated here
# 油温得热一点
We need the oil quite hot
# 您看油温七成热了
You see it's about 210°C
# 把凤爪炸成金黄色
Fry them to golden
# 炸出泡状的就可以了
and bubbles forming on the surface.
# 然后咱们把火关上
Then let's turn off the heat
# 然后把鸡爪子捞在冰水里边
Put chicken feet in ice water
# 激一下 一冷一热一激 皮更容易发泡
Bubbles will form with immediate hot and cold transition
# 虎皮的感觉就出来了
And we have the "Tiger Skin" looks
# 咱们把这个倒进去 得了你就炝锅吧
Let's pour them in a colander. Go heat up the wok.
# 那我这儿倒油了啊
I'll pour the oil
# 你倒你倒 虎皮状了
Go head. We have "Tiger Skin" now.
# 咱把葱姜下去 辣椒
Let's add green onion, ginger and dried chili peppers
# 把葱姜和辣椒煸出香味来
Bring out the aroma of those ingredients
# 咱们下点蒜蓉辣酱 煸炒一下
Let's add some minced garlic hot sauce and stir fry
# 这什么酱 柱候酱
What is this sauce? Chu Hou sauce.
# 再下入柱候酱
Then add Chu Hou sauce
# 把水烧开
Bring to a boil
# 咱们把炸好的凤爪放到锅里边
Let's put in the fried chicken feet
# 黄酒 酱油
Huangjiu rice wine and soy sauce
# 冰糖老抽
White rock sugar and dark soy sauce
# 你看
Salt (字幕和视频不符)
# 好
Sugar (字幕和视频不符)
# 下入蚝油 让它开锅
Add soy sauce and wait it to boil
# 师父您看这个 汤也比较红亮了
Master, you see the soup is brightening red.
# 汤也比较红亮了
# 就等它开锅 盖盖儿 焖上中火
Wait for it boil. Put on a lid and turn to middle heat.
# 中火 一干了就行了
Middle hear. Wait till the water is gone.
# 咱们中间打开锅看看
Let's check
# 你看
You see?
# 鸡爪子已经变大了
They have become larger in size
# 炸完以后它的吸汁儿性更强
They absorb the sauce better after frying
# 你看这凤爪上面
You see on their surface
# 都是一层麻点似的皮
there are sesame-like bubbles.
# 这就是刚才咱们炸完了起的气泡
These are the bubbles we had before
# 咱们出锅之前淋点香油
Spray some sesame oil before finished
# 葱姜辣椒都挑出去
Pick out green onion, ginger and dried chili peppers
# 收收汁儿
Thicken the sauce
# 出菜比较亮
Make the final dish pleasing to the eye
# 汤汁粘稠 网友喜欢这道菜
Sauce fully absorbed. Fans like this dish.
# 大爷先尝
Da Ye first
# 师父
Master
# 还吃的挺香
Looks delicious
# 怎么样 好吃
How is it? Good.
# 软烂入味儿
Soft and well-seasoned
# 二伯尝尝
Now Er Bai
# 斯文老头 斯文二伯
Er Bai is a mannerly old man
# 就这干辣椒 稍微把干辣椒去一去
If you could use less dried chili peppers,
# 你这菜就特别完美
this dish would be perfect.
# 我就说一个
One thing though
# 这只能叫热菜了
This is a hot dish
# 不能叫凉菜
Not a cold dish
# 大爷说的对 为什么呢
Da Ye is right. Why so?
# 凉菜要利索
Cold dish must be refreshing with simple and straightforward flavors
# 因为咱们烧的汁浓味厚
Since our sauce is thick and full of flavors,
# 有点热菜的这种风格
this dish is of a more hot dish style.
# 真正凉菜粤菜里边
Authentic chicken feet cold dish from Cantonese cuisine
# 凤爪特别利索
is very simple and straightforward in flavor.
# 而且酥 它那是蒸出来的
It's crispy, because of the steaming process.
# 所以它就爽
So it's refreshing
# 这个凤爪热着吃也可以 凉着吃也行
This chicken feet dish can be served hot or cold
# 这菜还真不错
This dish is great
# 大爷再来一块
Da Ye you want one more?
# 再来一块 好
One more. OK.
# 咱们有位网友叫岚马
Our fan named "Lan Ma"
# 他想问咸淡是怎么闻出来的
asked how saltiness can be smelled?
# 因为咸淡有时候闻
To smell the saltiness,
# 要分三步
there are 3 steps:
# 第一步是看
The first step is to see
# 我们比如说拌韭菜馅的饺子馅
We can take the Chinese chives dumpling filling for example
# 是吧
OK?
# 肉馅如果够咸了
If the meat is already salty enough,
# 这韭菜放进去
the Chinese chives
# 很快它就塌下来了
will wither and lose water very quickly once put in.
# 就给腌的蔫了
They are salted
# 茴香也是一样
Similar for fennel leaves
# 馅够咸不够咸
How to tell when the filling is salty enough?
# 我们在打馅的时候
We know that when mixing dumpling fillings,
# 肉刚开始松散
the minced meat is initially going to loose up.
# 经过我们打馅的过程当中
Then with more mixing,
# 它变成粘稠了
it will stick together again.
# 有劲儿了
Become thick
# 你看我们在一些菜谱的书里边
As some of the cooking manuals
# 会写到这么一句话
will tell you:
# 将肉馅放各种调味品
mix meat and other seasoning ingredients
# 搅拌上劲
until it becomes thick
# 包括上浆也是
Similar for mixing with starch
# 一上劲就说明它够咸了
Once becoming thick, it's salty enough
# 如果它不够咸
If not salty enough,
# 它就上不了劲儿
it will not stick so well
# 馅儿也是如此
It's the same for fillings
# 第二个是闻
The second step is to smell
# 因为我们放了很多调味品
If we put many seasonings in,
# 一闻馅儿就感觉特别香
we can smell the aroma of the various ingredients.
# 因为你没有盐
Without salt,
# 它的香味也产生不出来
the aroma won't come out.
# 是盐激发出来的香味
It's the salt at work here
# 第三个
The third step is -
# 是搅拌
to beat.
# 有的必要的时候
Sometimes when necessary,
# 我们还要品尝
we need to taste.
# 看有了闻有了
We see and smell
# 然后最后
And finally,
# 用我们的口腔和舌尖
we taste with our mouth and tongue to
# 来品尝菜咸与不咸
taste the saltiness.
# 比如说做一些酱汤
For example, to taste when making sauce soups
# 卤肉
and braised meat.
# 现在还有更科技的
Now we have more advanced tools
# 测盐的测温度的
that detect saltiness and temperature.
# 度量计 测盐计
Cooking thermometer and salt meter
# 一测你看
Just one test
# 今天我们冯肉肉
Today "Feng Rourou"
# 拿了一个测盐计
brings a salt meter.
# 一测  一滴汤就能测出
One test, with one drop of soup, can
# 它的盐度是七是八
tell the saltiness is at around 7 or 8.
# 不能超过十
Must be no more than 10
# 另外做这些酱味卤味的
In addition, for braised food,
# 这些菜
which
# 热做冷吃的
are cooked hot and served cold,
# 刚开始的味道是要咸一点
they should be a little bit saltier initially.
# 让它凉了以后
Once cool down,
# 它这咸味会降低
the saltiness will decrease.
# 所以要分三步看味道的
So we need 3 steps to see
# 咸 不咸
the saltiness of a dish.
# 好嘞 那请问二伯
OK. Now same question for Er Bai.
# 大爷说的很详细了
Da Ye has made it quite clear
# 其实我再补充两句
I want to offer some additional comments
# 首先选这个料
First of all the material
# 一定要新鲜
must be fresh,
# 才能调出好的味道来
for the best flavors.
# 第二就是刀工这一块
Second, knife skills are important
# 尽量让它要整齐
Try to make everything uniform
# 出来的味道才能一致
so that the flavor is the uniform as well.
# 再一个就是投味
The next thing is the right amount of seasoning
# 我们要投料这个味道
for the flavor we want to achieve.
# 比如说 我搁酱油也好
Either I want to add soy sauce,
# 搁盐也好
salt,
# 下味精也好下味道也好
or MSG,
# 基本就凭经验了
the amount of each is totally based on experiences.
# 眼看着搁多少盐差不多了
The amount of salt to put is totally by eyeball
# 比如一斤肉馅
For example, 0.5kg minced meat
# 我搁多少盐
requires how much salt?
# 搁几钱盐
How many grams of salt?
# 基本就有个大概齐
You should have a rough idea about that
# 最好的方法就是你倒约
The best method is to pour it out
# 我把盐约出一斤来
I pour out about 0.5kg of salt,
# 你直接约出这个数
with some rough measurement,
# 就扔进去就行了
and then just add it in.
# 有几种调味的
There are several
# 调味方式
seasoning order.
# 一种是烹调前加味儿
One is to season before cooking
# 有的原料块比较大
Some material comes in large chunks
# 不容易入味
They are difficult to season well
# 事先要给它加一些盐
So add some salt initially,
# 酱油
with some soy sauce,
# 一些调味品
and other seasoning ingredients.
# 它得腌制
To marinate first
# 还有烹调中加味
Also we can season in the middle of cooking.
# 尤其肉它蛋白质丰富
This is especially true for cooking meat, which is rich in protein.
# 你过早的放盐
If you add salt too early,
# 肉就不烂
the meat won't be easy to chew.
# 还有一个烹调后加味儿
And lastly to season after cooking
# 在最后
At the very last
# 就这个菜将要出锅的时候
Right before the dish is served
# 我们要定味儿
We want to preserve the final flavor
# 缺颜色
Not enough coloring?
# 补有点颜色缺盐
Add some coloring. Not enough salt?
# 我们可能还要加一些盐
We may need to add some salt
# 可能偶然间盐多了一点
Probably we add a little bit too much salt
# 你多了一点怎么办
What now?
# 咸了怎么办
What if it's too salty?
# 我们还要加点糖
We'd want to add some sugar
# 让这个味道更加厚重
to make the real flavor more subtle.
# 你看我们很多调味品
You see many seasoning ingredients
# 上面都有一些克度
have measurements.
# 比如说黄酒
For example, huangjiu rice wine
# 它含酒量一般在百分之十四
contains about 14% of alcohol.
# 就十四度
14%
# 醋就不同了
Vinegar is different
# 有五度的有八度的
It may contain 5% acetic acid or 8%
# 还有十三度的
Or even 13%
# 它那度数
That measurement
# 就是衡量原材料调味品
can determine how much origin material is used.
# 它的质地和它的味道
Also the texture and flavor
# 是浓是淡
to be thick or thin.
# 所以我们在烹调当中
So some cooking
# 像这种些知识
knowledges like these
# 是多方面的
are not very straightforward.
# 希望我们的网友
Hope our fans can
# 在这方面多了解一点
learn a little bit more on these.
# 好
OK!